New Delhi Delhi, India +91-9911813814

Experience Summary

With 3+ years of experience in the software industry, I come with expertise in Agile based development for web applications on Hybris platform, Java (core and advanced) and related technologies like Spring, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Spring MVC along with the domain knowledge in Ecommerce.

Work Experience

Nagarro Software – Associate, Technology

Jun 2016- Present

Ecommerce Implementation for a Cloud based PIM

Jan 2017 - Present

Hybris 5.4: Project involved the development of an e-commerce application with a cloud based product information management website to distribute and manage content through the Australian product catalogue to retail and manufacturer clients in Australia using Hybris Framework. As a developer, I am responsible for requirement analysis and design, solution architecture for backend and storefront management, user interface and user experience design.

I am responsible for creating Audit framework for the application to track the changes, exception handling, refactor code into different layers, accounts page and integrating the system with other third party client APIs. Solr customizations are also a part of my responsibilities.

System integration using RESTful APIs and importing data from Amazon cloud buckets.

Skills: Hybris | Java | Solr | Spring | jQuery | sql | Ajax | Bootstrap | SVN | Fly Framework

B2B E-commerce application

Jun 2016 – Jan 2017

Hybris 5.5: B2B application including a closed marketplace for one of the most renowned and influential diamond dealers in the world today. Features like Employee login from storefront, Sales Quote and Unit specific discounts. I was responsible for customizing the module for B2B Sales Quote provided by Hybris OOTB and thus took charge of all stages of development from requirement elicitation to delivery of the module.

Created web services for transaction like buy or quote via excel uploads.

Designed solution for additional marketing strategies, which were not supported by Hybris OOTB.

Creating cronjobs for marketing strategies used by the client and handling the Storefront for various modules.

Involved in visualizing, designing, implementing and deploying end to end workflow of the application.

Responsible for creating on Emails and their velocity templates.

Testing and bug fixing as per the process for the modules.

Skills: Hybris | Java | Spring | JavaScript | sql | Ajax | Bootstrap | GIT

Investors Portal

Jan 2016 – May 2016

I was responsible for creating RESTful APIs for an investment and finance related project on Spring and Hibernate. Creating APIs for goal planning, adjustments in the goal, file uploads and resolving bugs in the existing application. Adding Https support for the website by generating and deploying ssl certificates onto the server. Handling the entire backend for planning phase of the investments and deploying war files on amazon ebs server. Implementing OkHttp request and consuming other Https APIs to fetch fields for further calculations.

Skills: Java | Spring | LetsEncrypt | RESTful Web Services | sql | Json | EBS Server | Terminal | Git

Cognizant Technology Solutions - Programmer Analyst

Sep 2014 Jan 2016

Ecommerce Marketplace Implementation

Jul 2015 - Jan 2016

Hybris 5.5 Working in an Agile environment, I was responsible for creating CMS Components, Landing Pages, fragments, header and footer parts and writing their specific controllers, facades, service and Dao layers for both desktop and mobile sites. Proficient with HMC, HAC, WCMS, core data and sample data impex, internationalization and catalogues. Integrating JSPs with HTMLs, writing JavaScript code and creating ajax calls for different components. Integrating the system with shared DB, writing unit for Service layers, debugging the existing functionalities and server and doing Fit -Gap analysis for requirements.

Skills: Hybris | Java | Spring | JavaScript | sql | Ajax | Bootstrap | Git

Merchandise Store (Ecommerce)

Feb 2015- May 2015

Hybris 5.4 Ecommerce demo project to manage end to end process using Hybris as middle ware for the proposed system. Responsible for customising the demo website, adding facets, creating and modifying Impex files. Created **Fit Gap Analysis** document for client requirements.

Spring Login Application

May 2015

A simple POC for form handling SignUp application in Spring 3.0 MVC framework that helps user to perform SignUp and Login using Annotations, implementing interceptors and java Mail API for sending mails to registered users.

Skills: Spring | Spring MVC | Java | Bootstrap | Ajax

Repository: https://github.com/kuljeetsingh04/SpringFresh

Unilever PIM 2C

May 2015 - July 2015

Informatica Heiler PIM 7.1 MDM project to manage information of products in Informatica (Heiler 7.0) PIM. Responsible for creating Test Scenarios and Test Case Design and executing them. Testing the expected functionalities and interfaces with dependent systems like SAP ECC and Interspec.

Technical Skills

Languages	Java (core), J2EE, Spring 3, Spring 3 MVC, Ajax, JavaScript,
	jQuery, Json, C, C++, PL\SQL, SQL, HTML 5, CSS, Solr
Frameworks, Tools and	Spring, RESTful, Bootstrap, Hybris Multichannel commerce suit,
Libraries	Solr
Servers and Platforms	Apache Tomcat, Amazon EBS server, Jenkins
Databases & BI	Oracle 10g, MySQL, Hsql
Devices and OS	MS Windows, Linux
Softwares /	IntelliJ idea, Eclipse, GIT, Putty, Jira, Trello, Basecamp, Git Bash,
Components/ SDK	Sourcetree ,Sql Developer,Tortoise Git, Amazon EBS Server,
/Tools	MysqlWorkbench, terminal, letsencrypt, Okhttp, Jenkins, Svn,
	jMeter, jProfiler, blazemeter

Web Presence

Linkedin : Kuljeet SinghCodeChef : Kuljeet Singh

Education

Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology, Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi. Certification in German Language, St. Stephen's College, University of Delhi, Delhi